{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sodium chloride","incorrectAnswers":["Calcium magnesium carbonate","Trichloromethane","Iron Oxide"],"question":"What chemical has the formula NaCI?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Scandal in Bohemia'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Peter Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Moby-Dick","incorrectAnswers":["Pride and Prejudice","To Kill a Mockingbird","Great Expectations"],"question":"Which famous novel features the chapter titled 'Queequeg in His Coffin'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jude Watson","incorrectAnswers":["Stephenie Meyer","Philip K. Dick","Brandon Sanderson"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Star Wars: Jedi Apprentice'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Tadpole","incorrectAnswers":["A Calf","A Piglet","A Maggot"],"question":"What would you call a baby frog?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Eight","incorrectAnswers":["Four","Black","Nine"],"question":"In Italian, what is the meaning of the word 'otto'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sleep","incorrectAnswers":["Radiation","Earth materials","The eyes"],"question":"What is Hypnology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Riga","incorrectAnswers":["Maputo","Harare","Gitega"],"question":"What is the capital city of Latvia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Abraham Lincoln","incorrectAnswers":["Barack Obama","John Adams","Ronald Reagan"],"question":"Who was the first US president born outside the orginal 13 states","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Banjo","incorrectAnswers":["The Piano","The Harp","The Flute"],"question":"With Which Instrument Is Earl Scruggs Associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vietnam","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Scallop","incorrectAnswers":["Lobster","Oyster","Squid"],"question":"Coquille St Jaques is another name for which seafood?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sturgeon ","incorrectAnswers":["Trout","Salmon","Pollock"],"question":"From Which Fish Do You Obtain Caviar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Karl Marx","incorrectAnswers":["Jean Paul Sartre","Immanuel Kant","Jean-Jacques Rousseau"],"question":"Who wrote three books under the title \"Das Kapital\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Calvary","incorrectAnswers":["Lutheros","Pellenor","Idris"],"question":"What is the name of the field where Christ was crucified?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jules Verne","incorrectAnswers":["Victor Hugo","Alphonse Daudet","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Tribulations of a Chinaman in China'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Ice Hockey","incorrectAnswers":["American Football","Basketball","Tennis"],"question":"In which sport is the Canadian Wayne Gretzky an all time great?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Don Quixote","incorrectAnswers":["The Diary of a Chambermaid","The Neverending Story","Orlando Furioso"],"question":"In which book does 'Alonso Quijano' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kylie Minogue","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Mika","Hikaru Utada"],"question":"Which musician released the studio album 'Light Years'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Geology","incorrectAnswers":["Astronomy","Magnetism","Meteorology"],"question":"What is the name of the science that studies the origin, history, and structure of the Earth?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Pittsburgh Pirates","incorrectAnswers":["Pittsburgh Pistons","Pittsburgh Braves","Pittsburgh Astros"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Pittsburgh?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Home Alone","incorrectAnswers":["Blue Velvet","On the Waterfront","Mad Max"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Kevin McCallister'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Titan","incorrectAnswers":["Io","Europa","Luna"],"question":"Which moon is the second largest satellite in our solar system?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Buoyancy","incorrectAnswers":["Liquefaction","Oscillation","Gravity"],"question":"What is the term for the tendency of an object to float, or the upward pressure of fluid in an object?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Madonna","Mika"],"question":"Which British musician released the album 'Station to Station'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Black","Blue","Green"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of China?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which American singer released the song 'Human Nature'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fresco","incorrectAnswers":["Mosaic","Graffiti","Stencil"],"question":"What term refers to a type of mural painting executed on freshly laid, still-wet plaster, with water-based pigments?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Man with the Golden Gun","incorrectAnswers":["Dr. No","Live and Let Die","Spectre"],"question":"Which James Bond theme song was performed by Lulu?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mad Men","incorrectAnswers":["Breaking Bad","The Sopranos","The Wire"],"question":"Which TV show featured characters named Peggy Olson and Joan Holloway?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Nicki Minaj","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which musician released the studio album 'American Life'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Ceylon","incorrectAnswers":["Burma","East Pakistan","Persia"],"question":"What is the former name of Sri Lanka?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Czechoslovakia","incorrectAnswers":["Hungary","Yugoslavia","Belarus"],"question":"In 1968 Which Country Did The USSR Invade To Stamp Out Liberal Reform?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"AC/DC","incorrectAnswers":["Pendulum","INXS","Savage Garden"],"question":"Which Australian hard rock band released the studio album 'Back in Black'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"To the Lighthouse","incorrectAnswers":["The Sound and the Fury","Ulysses","All the King's Men"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Mrs. Ramsay'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"2001","incorrectAnswers":["1992","1995","1998"],"question":"In which year was The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"March 17th","incorrectAnswers":["March 14th","February 15th","February 16th"],"question":"What date is St. Patrick's Day? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Once Upon a Time in America","incorrectAnswers":["Goodfellas","Gone with the Wind","There Will Be Blood"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A former gangster returns home, where he must confront the regrets of his old life.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Peru","incorrectAnswers":["Algeria","Papua New Guinea","Finland"],"question":"Where are the Nazca Lines?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Tupac","incorrectAnswers":["Notorious B.I.G.","Nas","Snoop Dogg"],"question":"Which rapper released the song 'California Love'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Eclair","incorrectAnswers":["Strudel","Kringle","Cannoli"],"question":"What is the name of a pastry traditionally made with choux dough, filled with cream and topped with a flavored icing?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Washington Irving","incorrectAnswers":["Suzanne Collins","James Fenimore Cooper","Donna Leon"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Legend of Sleepy Hollow'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Little Red Riding Hood","incorrectAnswers":["Hey Diddle Diddle","Mary Had a Little Lamb","Baa Baa Black Sheep"],"question":"What nursery rhyme is about a girl who went to the woods?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A herd","incorrectAnswers":["A sloth","A muster","A brace"],"question":"What is the word for a group of swine?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Egg Mcmuffin","incorrectAnswers":["MSG","Aqua Faba","Instant Noodles"],"question":"What did Herb Peterson invent?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Denmark","Germany","Kingdom of the Netherlands"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Norway?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Fleetwood Mac","incorrectAnswers":["W.A.S.P.","Paramore","Alice in Chains"],"question":"Which band includes 'Lindsey Buckingham'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Margaret Thatcher","incorrectAnswers":["Angela Merkel","Valerie Du Pont","Herscha Vogel"],"question":"Who was the first woman elected to lead a European democracy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"What a dump.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"May the odds ever be in your favor.\"","\"We’re goin’ streaking!\"","\"Mother of mercy, is this the end of Rico?\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Beyond the Forest'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tobey Maguire","incorrectAnswers":["Warwick Davis","Timothy Spall","Hugo Weaving"],"question":"Which actor has starred in both Spider-Man and The Great Gatsby?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kazakhstan","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Tajikistan","Azerbaijan"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Nur Sultan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Butterfly","incorrectAnswers":["Dragonfly","Mayfly","Horsefly"],"question":"Which Swimming Stroke Was Introduced Into Competition In 1952","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sunny","incorrectAnswers":["Rainy","Cloudy","Stormy"],"question":"What adjective completes the TV show title, \"It's Always ____ in Philadelphia\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Clue","incorrectAnswers":["Checkers","Backgammon","Scrabble"],"question":"What is the name of the classic board game where players must discover the circumstances of a murder?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Banshee","incorrectAnswers":["Gremlin","Wraith","Poltergeist"],"question":"What do the Irish call a spirit whose wailing signals imminent death?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mammary gland","incorrectAnswers":["Prostate","Pancreas","Pituitary gland"],"question":"In mammals , which organ produces milk?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Laxative","incorrectAnswers":["Analgesic","Anti inflammatory","Suppository"],"question":"What is the word for a medicine that hastens the emptying of the bowels?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The origin of life","incorrectAnswers":["Black holes","The ecology of any individual species","The biosphere"],"question":"What is astrobiology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Duke of Wellington","incorrectAnswers":["Horatio Nelson","Gebhard Leberecht von Blücher","Charles-Maurice de Talleyrand"],"question":"Who was the British commander at the Battle of Waterloo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Jenever","incorrectAnswers":["Brennivín","Akevitt","Gin"],"question":"Which of these drinks would you associate with Belgium?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"fricative","incorrectAnswers":["plosive","approximant","nasal"],"question":"In phonetics, the z in 'zoo' is an example of what kind of sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Les Misérables","incorrectAnswers":["Phantom of the Opera","Cats","Hamilton"],"question":"Which musical features the songs 'The People's Song' and 'Paris'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ridley Scott","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Blade Runner?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Rutherford B. Hayes","incorrectAnswers":["Harry S. Truman","George W. Bush","George Washington "],"question":"Who was the 19th president of the USA, in term during the period 1877–1881?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Chinese philosopher.","incorrectAnswers":["Greek politician","Russian theoretical physicist","Mongolian General"],"question":"Which of the following describes Confucius?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Godfather Part II","incorrectAnswers":["Chinatown","The Conversation","Lenny"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1974?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Just keep swimming.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Tell 'em to go out there with all they got and win just one for the Gipper.\"","\"We'll always have Paris.\"","\"Today, I consider myself the luckiest man on the face of the earth.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Finding Nemo'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cycling","incorrectAnswers":["American Football","Cricket","Tennis"],"question":"What sport would you associate with The Tour de France?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belarus","incorrectAnswers":["Bulgaria","Lithuania","Latvia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Ukraine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ernst Stavro Blofeld","incorrectAnswers":["Auric Goldfinger","Francisco Scaramanga","Max Zorin"],"question":"Which diabolical James Bond nemesis has been portrayed by both Donald Pleasance and Charles Gray?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Pup","incorrectAnswers":["A Tadpole","A Codling","A Calf"],"question":"What is the word for a young shark?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tanzania","incorrectAnswers":["Zimbabwe","Burundi","Comoros"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Malawi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Jerusalem","incorrectAnswers":["Paris","Rome","Istanbul"],"question":"The \"Old City\" of this location is divided into four quarters — a Christian quarter, a Muslim Quarter, a Jewish Quarter, and an Armenian Quarter.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kazakhstan","incorrectAnswers":["Georgia","Poland","Vietnam"],"question":"Which of these countries has blue on its flag?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gabriel García Márquez","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","Søren Kierkegaard","Voltaire"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Strange Pilgrims'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Monkees","incorrectAnswers":["The Brady Bunch","Gilligan's Island","Bewitched"],"question":"What classic TV show from the 1960s featured the theme song with the following lyrics: 'Here we come, walkin' down the street, we get the funniest looks from everyone we meet'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sloe ","incorrectAnswers":["Liquorice","Coriander","Quinine"],"question":"Often Used In The Production Of Spirits, What Is The Fruit Of The Blackthorn Tree Called?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sean Connery","incorrectAnswers":["Laurence Fishburne","George Clooney","James Franco"],"question":"Which James Bond actor played the role in Dr. No and Thunderball?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Radar","incorrectAnswers":["Smash","Internet","LOL"],"question":"Which of these is an example of a palindrome?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"50 Pence","incorrectAnswers":["£2","20 Pence","15 Pence"],"question":"In 1968 Which British Coin Was Introduced To Replace The Ten Shilling Note?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Canada","incorrectAnswers":["Australia","Turkey","Mexico"],"question":"Ottawa is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Michigan","incorrectAnswers":["Florida","Nevada","Idaho"],"question":"Which US state is divided into two parts by a large lake?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Martin Luther","incorrectAnswers":["Asoka","Louis Daguerre","Gregor Mendel"],"question":"Which influential historical person sought to reform the Roman Catholic Church - starting the Protestant Reformation?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Edmonton Oilers","incorrectAnswers":["Edmonton Steelers","Edmonton Eathquakes","Edmonton Padres"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Edmonton?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Deep Purple","incorrectAnswers":["UB40","Keane","The Cure"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'Machine Head'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bull","incorrectAnswers":["A Tom","A Macho","A Buck"],"question":"A male seal is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"King Solomon's Mines","incorrectAnswers":["Treasure Island","Heart of Darkness","The Lost World"],"question":"What is the title of the 1885 adventure novel that chronicles the search for legendary horde of treasure in Africa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Bronx ","incorrectAnswers":["Brooklyn","Staten Island","The Jersey Shore"],"question":"Which Borough of New York is northeast of and adjacent to Manhattan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sol","incorrectAnswers":["Ursa Minor","Proxima Centauri","Epsilon Eridani"],"question":"Which star is nearest the Earth?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tuvalu","incorrectAnswers":["Latvia","The Vatican","Tibet"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.tv' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"23","incorrectAnswers":["211","5","42"],"question":"How many tales are there in Chaucer's Canterbury tales?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ireland","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Hungary","Latvia"],"question":"Dublin is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indian summer","incorrectAnswers":["Autumn solstice","Fall warming","Harvest heating"],"question":"What is the term for a period of unusually warm weather in the autumn?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Frankenstein","incorrectAnswers":["Cloud Atlas","Coraline","Strange Case of Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'You will rejoice to hear that no disaster has accompanied the commencement of an enterprise which you have regarded with such evil forebodings.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rushmore","incorrectAnswers":["Yellowstone","Everest","Fairweather"],"question":"On what mountain are four presidents' faces carved? ","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Prohibition","incorrectAnswers":["The Dry Spell","The Dark Days","The Moonshine"],"question":"What Name Was Given To The Period From 1919 To 1933 When Alcohol Was Banned In The USA?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Honey ","incorrectAnswers":["Almond","Grape","Potato"],"question":"What Is the Main Ingredient Of The Liquor Mead? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Detroit","incorrectAnswers":["Mojave","Denver","Las Vegas"],"question":"From which city's nickname is Motown's name derived?","difficulty":"hard"},